Which is the best health
insurance plan for you, we will discuss it in detail
in today's video.  I will tell you
which health
insurance plan I have taken myself.  What
pointers have I taken into consideration and
what is the reason behind the plan I have taken?
You will get the explanation in detail.
Everything from basic to advanced will be covered.
So this is a very important video.  Please
like it now.  Let's get started.
First of all you have to understand
what is health insurance?  An
insurance that will provide security to you and your family when
you are
on a hospital bed.  If you fall ill, we
call it a health insurance plan.  Meaning,
after taking this plan, if you have any medical
expenditure, your health deteriorates
, you get admitted in the hospital, then
all the expenditure at that time will be taken care of.  There are
two types of health insurance plans available to us.  The first
is the individual plan.  In this plan,
you take health insurance plan for only one person
and you get coverage only
for that particular person.  For
example, if I
take a health insurance plan for myself, an
individual policy, then only I will be covered in that policy.
My related
complete expenses will be covered there.
Second is the family
floater for you.  Now what is a family floater?
For me, this is the health insurance panel in family floater.
But at the same
time, he has also got his wife and child
covered under the same health insurance.
And because this is a family
floater plan for the complete family.  We all
also get proper health insurance coverage.  More than that, the
premium of a complete family floater
plan
becomes very cheap for every individual as compared to an individual plan.  This means that
taking a family floater plan is always a
better choice for you.  Now, to begin with, let me
tell you which
health insurance plan I have taken for myself.  You
can check out on the screen right now.  The
name of my health insurance plan is HDFC
Argo Optima Secure Health Insurance
Plan.  Now first of all you should understand why I have taken this HDFC Ergo Optima
Secure
and first of all you should also see
that in the health
insurance plan that I have taken for myself, I have already included my son
Daivik.
Meaning, right now he would be only three and a half years old
but still he is getting proper coverage.
You can check out the complete here.  The
data has appeared on your screen.  Meaning
when we include our small children also
in our family floater plan.
They also get coverage.  Sometimes I suppose
he had a health insurance
related requirement.  If any health
condition arises, their expenses will also be covered.  The
premium will also be low because
I have taken this plan for them at a very early age
and in this way we
can plan properly.  Keep one thing in mind
while taking a health insurance family floater plan.  Do
not include your elderly parents in your plan.
Take a separate plan for them.  Because when there is a family floater plan, a
lot depends on the oldest person as to how much
premium you will have to pay.  If you have
included your wife and children in your plan, it is a very good thing.
But if you include your elderly parents
in the same plan because they are
older and there is a
possibility of higher health insurance claims.  Their
premium will be higher.
Due to the higher cost, the premium of your complete plan will
increase significantly.  Please keep this thing in mind.
Now let me explain it to you in detail.  Look,
I have told you completely which one I have
taken.  Now why have you taken it,
I will divide it into seven simple points for you.  The
first pointer is 4x
coverage at no additional cost.  You get all three – Secure
Benefit, Plus Benefit and Ratio Benefit
together.  Now what does this mean
?  Let us understand in detail.  Suppose
I have taken a sum insured of ₹5 lakh.
As soon as I take the policy,
my sum insured immediately increases from Rs 5 lakh to
double 5 + 5 i.e. Rs 10 lakh.
We call this secure benefit.
Seconds.  Now I am going to explain to you the plus
benefits.  As soon as my first renewal comes
, my sum insured increases from Rs 10 lakh to Rs
12.5 lakh.  And as soon as the second
renewal comes, this plus benefit continues again after increasing from Rs 12.5 lakh
and
my complete sum insured becomes Rs 15
lakh.  I started with a policy of just Rs 5
lakh.  Immediately my secure
benefit increased to Rs 10 lakh.  As soon as
my Plus Benefit got activated, my
complete policy became worth Rs 15 lakh.  And
finally the restore benefit is activated in front of us.
If I ever make a
claim, my Basic Sum Insured will be
automatically restored up to 100%.   That
means my basic sum insured was Rs 5 lakh.
As soon as I make a claim, this Rs
5 lakh will be restored immediately.  This means that the
basic policy that I had of Rs 5 lakh,
effectively becomes Rs 20 lakh instead of Rs 5 lakh.   This
means that you get up to 4x coverage without paying any extra premium.
That too within
two years.  The first is secure
benefit.  Second is Plus Benefit and
finally Restore Benefit.  By combining all three
you get four X coverage.
Second point zero deduction on listed
non-medical expenses.  See, nowadays
most of the policies include
gloves, bandages, surgical tapes and
many such non-medical items, the
complete list of which I have just
put on your screen.  You have to
pay them from your own pocket.  But
here in this particular plan,
all the consumables are included.
Meaning, when the claim comes, we will
easily get the claim for this also.   There will be no
unnecessary hidden deductions.
We don't have to worry about that.  This
is a small but very important pointer because
when you have to pay for the consumable later,
you think that friend, I had taken the
policy, now why are you asking me for something unnecessary, keep this in mind that
your premium can start from ₹27 per
day, see this policy is going to be financially
quite reasonable for you, for example,
if you are 30 years old and
want to take sum insured of Rs 5 lakh, then the premium will
roughly start from ₹27 per day,
especially if you buy online, which means the
premium of this complete policy
is quite reasonable.  We all need health insurance.
As soon as we
start earning our first salary, getting a complete
family floater plan health
insurance becomes so important and it
fulfils our requirement in that complete situation.
Forth Point comes with 15,000 plus cashless
healthcare providers.
You get quality care in every corner of India.
That is why the cashless hospital network of this plan
is quite strong.  15,000 plus
hospitals and diagnostic centers will already
provide you easy treatment here.
Where your work will be done without cash case settlement.
Still as an
additional point as a brother you consider me.
So let me tell you one more additional point.
Whenever you take this policy, please check it.
Your main location is the
main hospital near where you live.  Plus if you suppose you
live in a small city.
When you go to a big city, which
hospital would you like to go to?  Go and
check it.  In majority of situations,
you are going to get cashless settlement of HDFC Argo.
But please do check this thing.
This will be an added
advantage for you.  Whenever we get admitted to a hospital
, we want to
get all the treatment cashless.  Unnecessary
once you don't have to pay cash.
What happens sometimes?  There are some policies
which say we will reimburse you.
You pay once.  Hey brother, if
I had to pay only once then
why would I take health insurance?  I do
n't have money to make a one-time payment and I am
spending a lot here.  That's why
I have taken a health insurance
plan.  Therefore, we never
want to have to pay for something unnecessary once.
Having cashless settlement becomes very
important for us.
Fifteenth point comes,
they have already settled the health insurance claim of plus Rs 24,000 crore.
In health insurance, HDFC Ergo has
settled health insurance claims worth over Rs 24,000 crore.  And
when the claim settlement of our company is quite
high, then we have confidence
that in times of trouble, my claim will also be
passed here.  Unnecessary, I will
not be given any delay here.  More than that
I always say that whenever you
take a health insurance plan, always
look at the brand of the company.  Because
even in times of trouble, if the company's brand name
grows, then unnecessary claims will not
stop you.  She will not bother you because
she will be worried about her brand.  For
example, in the Covid situation, there were many
small health insurance companies which
started rejecting unnecessary claims.
He was in trouble and his
survival was at stake.  But at the same
time, if there is any big brand, for
example, let us talk about HDFC Bank.
They had done timely settlement even
during Covid, so at such a time, having a big
brand increases our confidence.
And whatever pointers I am giving here, all these are the
same pointers which
convinced me about which health
insurance plan I should take.  And
with the same transparency and simplicity, I am
presenting the points before you
so that you too can take simple and easy decision making.
And the final point is 3.2
crore plus happy customers.  See,
having a happy customer base of 3.2 crore plus
is a big figure which signifies a trust.  It
signifies the brand and
also clearly shows us that the company is
here for the long term.
I personally have long term confidence in this brand
and because of this I am able to get
this comfort here.  Finally, if
I
try to summarize the complete video, then I have shared all the features and
important pointers and valuable pointers with
you.  And for these
reasons, I took this complete health
insurance plan and added my child
also.  I just had another baby 15 days ago.
As soon as his name is
finalised,
I am going to add him to my family floater plan.
See, health insurance is such an
insurance which we need
for everyone.  Will help us in difficult situations.
So the name has not been finalized yet.  As soon as the name is
finalized, his name will also be
added to the health insurance family floater.
You should also always insure this thing.
So, if you are looking for
a solid, reliable and feature-rich health
insurance plan for your family,
then HDFC Optima Secure is a must-
consider option.  You should do your studies properly.
But I have presented a good option
before you.  If you
want more details about this plan,
you can check out the description and pin comment.
And always keep in mind that
whatever health insurance emergency happens, it does
not come to you with any prior notice.  She comes randomly
out of nowhere.  Better be safe than
sorry.  You will find all the important links
in the pin comments and description.
Happy learning and I will see you very soon.